# JORDAN "JJ" CARDENAS

Woodinville, WA

Phone: 425-922-3350 | Email: jj@jjcardenas.com

**LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/jordanjcardenas | **GitHub:** github.com/cardeens

Portfolio: www.jjcardenas.com

#### SUMMARY

Web developer and recent graduate of an intensive full stack development program backed by five years as a marketing professional in the technology industry. Organized, personable, fast learner seeking a role with a product team where I can combine my marketing knowledge with my new-found technical skills to help reach millions by building the next great experience.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, Node.js, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Handlebars.js,

Express, MERN Stack

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Deployment & Version Control: Git, Heroku, GoDaddy

Project Tracking: JIRA. Confluence. Trello

## **PROJECTS**

# Quiz Panda | https://github.com/sali6798/quiz-panda | https://quizpanda.herokuapp.com/

Simple and responsive application that allows users to create surveys and quizzes and share them with friends via email to see who can get the highest score

- Participated with a team of four in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging
- Demonstrated strong written and verbal communication skills using Zoom and Slack to collaborate remotely and presenting final application to classmates and instructors
- Led front-end development by brainstorming the overall the user experience, creating user stories and wireframes, and coding with Handlebars, JavaScript, HTML, and Foundation CSS package
- Awards: Best App Overall, Best UI

# MGR | https://github.com/sali6798/mgr-react | https://mgr-talent.herokuapp.com/

Marketing automation tool targeted to the music industry to help record label staff manage social media efforts for their artists

- Two-week team project with agile approach and remote SCRUM meetings
- Led UX strategy and front-end development with React and Material-UI, with the final application ultimately winning the award for Best UI
- Implemented Node packages such as Nodemailer, Express, BCrypt, Uniqid dotenv, and Cron
- Thoroughly documented all code changes through a front-end and back-end repository in GitHub to follow versioning best practices

#### Google Books | github.com/cardeens/googlebooks | ji-googlebooksfinal.herokuapp.com

Responsive application that uses the Google Books API to search for books and allows users to save or remove titles from their Saved list

- Built individually using MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) and routed search queries from Google Books API
- Thorough testing, troubleshooting, and debugging across front and back end code to create functional and responsive application
- Deployed final application through Heroku and have continued to push continuous improvements

## FINDR | https://github.com/cardeens/FindrApp | https://cardeens.github.io/FindrApp/index.html

Simple and user-friendly application that randomly displays an image from a restaurant in a card that can be cycled through until an appealing option is picked. Once the top choice is chosen, the restaurant information will be shown to get a user to their food as fast as possible

- Initially led a team of four as Project Manager in a one-week period to develop, debug, and deploy application using the Zomato and Google Maps APIs on the back end and Bootstrap to format the front end
- After the program, individually took initiative and updated the app to use Yelp Fusion API in an effort to continuously improve the app and provide the best possible user experience

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Web Developer Consultant
Pennaz Software

July 2020 – Present
Woodinville, WA

Operating in a consulting capacity to support the content and design strategy to launch company's main website along with other key web components

Key Accomplishments:

- Utilize daily standups to communicate project plan and milestones and have met 100% of deadlines set across strategy, design review, and launch phases
- Built out content across entire website to communicate company offerings and showcase deployed applications, and coded website using React.js, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, and several node packages

Marketing Strategy Consultant July 2019 – March 2020

Lenati LLC Seattle, WA

Worked independently across key account such as Microsoft, T-Mobile, and Vans to drive several successful, high-visibility marketing and program management projects Key Accomplishments:

- Coordinated SMEs across engineering, product marketing, and executive teams to create Microsoft Ignite
  presentation and PR content that aligned with product vision and strategy, and ultimately achieved the
  highest participant satisfaction rating across business groups
- Set and surpassed milestones for Pluralsight training modules pushed to production while acting as a project manager and successfully creating and executing workflows, presenting progress to managers, and identifying technical and business requirements

**Sr. Marketing Specialist** March 2016 – July 2019

Xevo Inc. Bellevue, WA

Collaborated cross-functionally in a fast-paced, constantly changing startup environment to support and lead marketing programs and product development efforts Key Accomplishments:

- Worked with senior leadership to rebrand company and build out new web, print, and video content to support the company's new brand and positioning in the AI/ML space
- Built and maintained client relationships and supported vendors to drive platform onboarding and crosspromotion plans, with multiple GTM campaigns increasing MAUs by over 150%
- Applied critical thinking while working with UX team to create best possible user experience for new cuttingedge applications that aligned with business requirements, bringing a brand-new set of connected-car experiences to market while consistently meeting release and user activity KPIs

Account Executive July 2015 – February 2016

Digital Intelligence Systems Kirkland, WA

Eagerly took on key ownership to manage accounts within the high-tech industry vertical, namely Microsoft and Facebook

Key Accomplishments:

Proactively built trusting and personable relationships with hiring managers at client sites by building an
understanding of team needs and transforming feedback into actionable requirements

# **VOLUNTEER**

Social Media Strategist July 2016 – March 2019

HERE Seattle Seattle, WA

Led marketing programs and community engagement efforts on the leadership team for a non-profit dedicated to supporting an inclusive culture in technology and making a positive impact in the Seattle community

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Development Certificate: University of Washington, Seattle, WA May 2020

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

**BA in Business Administration, Marketing Major:** Seattle University, Seattle, WA June 2015

Dean's List for Albers School of Business and Economics (Fall 2013-Spring 2015)